a few weeks ago I released uh videos on
Deet versus natural repellent that we
can apply to our clothes or skin but uh
can the things we eat also have a
repellent quality
no word yet on vampires but we do have
an events on garlic and other blood
suckers check it out
[Music]
are some people just more attractive to
mosquitoes than others apparently so as
identical twins are most likely to be
similarly tasty compared to fraternal
twins who will only share 50 of their
DNA demonstrating an underlying genetic
component that can be sniffed out by
mosquitoes although it's not clear it's
because some people smell better or
other people just smell worse we know
pregnant women are twice as attractive
to malaria mosquitoes and also that
mosquitoes are attracted to sweat human
sweat contains components that are
attractive to anthropophilic meaning
human loving mosquitoes the unique
composition of human sweat appears to
explain its tantalizing effect though
sweat from some body parts are evidently
more tantalizing than others skin
emanation is collected from armpits were
less attractive compared to hands or
feet here's the graph they think the
difference may be caused by deodorant
residues since in a subsequent
experiment volunteers were asked to
avoid using skin care products for five
days and after that no differences were
detected
the creepiest bit of research I found
was this the parasites that caused the
mosquito-borne disease malaria which
kills hundreds of thousands of people a
year makes you more attractive to you
guessed it the mosquitoes that transmit
malaria what better way for the
parasites to Hitch from person to person
instead of leaving it up to Chance some
parasites manipulate their hosts in
elaborate ways I've talked about how the
Toxoplasma brain parasite draws mice to
the smell of cat urine to get into cats
brains or how about the rabies virus
concentrating in the saliva while
tapping into the Cujo raid circuit in
the brain there's even a parasite that
needs to get from an ant to a bird so it
turns the ant's belly bright red to look
like a ripe Berry and makes the ant
stick it up in the air to confuse the
fruit-eating bird here's the ants before
and after infection just like most
malaria parasites making us particularly
tasty to mosquitoes
anything we can do to make ourselves
less tasty I've talked about the various
mosquito repellents you can spray on
your skin both synthetic and natural
mosquito repellent but is there anything
you can eat or drink to make you less of
a Target
when you search the scientific
literature for diet and mosquitoes a lot
of Articles like this pop up on diets
four mosquitoes like sketo snack for
that artificial blood meal replacement
feeding mice different diets makes a
difference but what about people
one of the most common anecdotes is that
vitamin B complex supplements protect
against biting insects other anecdotal
remedies include the taking of garlic
Marmite Vegemite brewers yeast tablets
and alcohol but you don't know
until you put it to the test how about a
randomized double blind
placebo-controlled trial of garlic as a
mosquito repellent a belief in the
ability of garlic to repel insects seems
to be widespread so researchers in
Connecticut decided to see if it were
true they looked at the numbers of
mosquitoes that did not feed on the
subjects the number of mosquito bites
the weights of the mosquitoes after
feeding and the amount of blood ingested
all determined on people on and off
garlic and the data did not provide
evidence of significant mosquito
repellents no surprise given that even
if you slather garlic oil on your skin
within 30 minutes mosquitoes don't seem
to care
eating Garlic May however help against
ticks because military personnel can
sometimes be a particularly high risk
for tick bites and tick-borne diseases
the Swedish military conducted
randomized controlled double-blind
Trials of garlic to prevent tick bites
among Marines 50 swallowed the
equivalent of about a clove a day of
garlic and 50 took Placebo pills then
they all switched and there was a
significant reduction in tick bites when
consuming garlic compared to Placebo
cutting the risk of tick bites by about
20 percent
20 is better than nothing but treating
your clothing with something like
Permethrin has been shown to be a
hundred percent effective against deer
ticks the vector of Lyme disease and so
that may be better than counting on
garlic bread to save you
[Music]
foreign